<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Thrive Healthfully]]></title>
  <link href="http://thrive-healthfully.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://thrive-healthfully.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-04-12T14:06:15-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://thrive-healthfully.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ben Augarten]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Thrive Healthfully?]]></title>
    <link href="http://thrive-healthfully.github.io/blog/2017/04/12/why-thrive-healthfully/"/>
    <updated>2017-04-12T13:40:10-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://thrive-healthfully.github.io/blog/2017/04/12/why-thrive-healthfully</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I didn’t always think about my health. I ate junk food (I believed apples to be ‘too healthy’ to enter my body), drank heavily, and slept less than 6 hours nearly every night, despite having already been diagnosed with arthritis (at age 13), depression (age 14), and psoriasis (age 17). After months suffering from indigestion and pain, I saw a gastroenterologist who rushed me in for a next day colonoscopy. I woke in a daze to a stern doctor warning me of impending surgery and hospitalization; that was the day everything changed.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I did research, read, and self-experimented. I tried the fruit-only diet and raw vegan diet, and finally found the <a href="https://www.thepaleomom.com/start-here/the-autoimmune-protocol/">Autoimmune Protocol</a> (AIP) and <a href="http://www.breakingtheviciouscycle.info/p/beginners-guide/">Specific Carbohydrate Diet</a> (SCD). After years of hard work, compliance, and trial and error, I’ve managed to go off of my medications completely (Humira and Mesalamine), and live a relatively normal life. Sometimes I go through periods of mild symptoms and other times I enjoy a happiness that I had never known: my journey from disease and back profoundly shifted my priorities, outlook, and relationship with myself and others.</p>

<p>I started <a href="https://www.thrivehealthfully.com/">Thrive Healthfully</a> to deliver seriously delicious, nutritious meals to people improving their health through diet and lifestyle. I want to help guide others along the path that so many inspirational figures in the health and wellness space are working to clear. These figures have formalized how to use food as medicine, replicated their results across their patients, and broadcasted their results to the world. They have published diet and lifestyle modifications to recover from many of the chronic ills that plague us, but ultimately every individual faces a trade-off between how harmful their symptoms are and how intrusive the modifications are to implement. Individuals with depression, anxiety, acne, fatigue, indigestion, brain fog and other undiagnosable malaise, as well as autoimmune disease such as MS, rheumatoid arthritis, hypo(hyper)thyroidism, and inflammatory bowel disease are forced to choose between accepting their condition, medication, and status quo and profoundly changing their life, a terrifying prospect.</p>

<p>The recommended response to these kinds of symptoms and diagnoses tend to combine dietary intervention, stress reduction and management techniques, and, when indicated through laboratory testing, toxin removal. However, medical practitioners only see their patients infrequently, and the burden of acquiring information, especially when it comes to dietary changes, lands on the patient. Needing to cook three meals each day, aiming to consume 9+ cups of vegetables and all the fatty fish, wild and grass fed meat you can eat, from scratch is a large burden, especially when placed on top of existing priorities and other mouths to feed.</p>

<p>I hope that through delivering tasty, ready to eat meals that are packed with nutrients, Thrive can provide that extra boost to enable people to make the leap towards health. I want Thrive to empower everyone improving their health to effectively utilize nutritional therapy as a cornerstone of their journey to health.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
